Ovarro Hanson

160B Attingham Drive, Dudley, DY1 3HY Phone (mobile): 07498167172 - <u>ovarrohanson18@yahoo.com</u>,

linkedin.com/in/ovarro-hanson, https://github.com/Ohanson18

Professional summary

I am a dedicated and versatile professional with ten years of expertise in combined management and customer service, along with a passion for AWS services. I have a proven record of reliability, problem-solving skills and obtaining results to meet the requirements of local customers and international business partners. I recently completed 12 weeks of intense training with Generation on the AWS re/Start program. This was done remotely where I Gained experience and knowledge in the following: IT fundamental skills in Python, Linux Operating system, Databases, Networking and AWS cloud computing. I am keen to put this training into action and further develop my skills, as I work towards my career goal of becoming a cloud solutions architecture.

Skill

- Linux
- Python
- Networking
- AWS-cloud computing concepts and core services
- Time management
- Customer service
- Critical thinking
- Administration and management

Experience

15/07/2020 09/2020

AWS re/Start program

Cloud Ops engineer (trainee)

- Covered Linux (CLI), Networking, Security, Introduction to programming and databases, Python, Cloud Computing concepts and core services.
- Labs that provided me hands on experience using AWS services such as writing code and using Lambda to trigger events

05/2013 to 11/2019

Property Manager

Bromfield's Property - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections and disbursements, and ensure that accounts are balanced.
- Meet with prospective tenants to show properties and explain terms of occupancy.
- Act as liaisons between tenants and owners.

- Investigate complaints, disturbances and violations and resolve problems following management rules and regulations.
- This role allowed me to build excellent communication and persuasive skills, along with improving my numerical reasoning.

03/2013 to 11/2019

General Manager

Young Dreamers Research Centre - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Use computers for various applications, such as database management and word processing.
- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections and disbursements, and ensure that accounts are balanced.
- Operate office equipment, such as: copiers or phone systems, configuring router and arrange for repairs when equipment malfunctions.
- In this role I learned how to take personal responsibility, demonstrated teamwork, adopted growth mindset and persistence.

09/2018 to 10/2019

Private Hire Taxi

Self Employed - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Follow safety regulations and laws governing vehicle operation, and ensure that passengers follow safety regulations.
- Arrange to pick up particular customers or groups on a regular schedule.
- This job allowed me to better develop my customer service and time management skills.

Education

03/2020 Generation UK and Ireland

Facilitator for the AWS re/start program

07/2009 Human Employment and Resource Training Trust/National Training Agency

Electrical Installation: level 2 -the equivalent to BTEC DIPLOMAS

Interests & Achievement

09/03/2020

Highfield level 2 award in the principles of fire safety (RQF)